Jiecheng Luo

Research Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, University College London 1-19 Torrington Place, London, WC1E 7HB jiecheng.luo.20@ucl.ac.uk

+86 (180) 7507 6866, +1 (320) 433 0484

I'm a self-motivated PhD student who has developed research quantitative and analytical skills with a strong capacity to conduct independent research. I am interested in developing a career that combines teaching and research, while maintaining my interest in public engagement on ageing into disability.

Education

University College London (2020-present), PhD

- Enrolled in the PhD programme of Epidemiology and Public Health.
- Self-funded research project titled 'Disability and social relationships among older adults in China'.
- Joint supervisors: Professor Anne McMunn and Dr Baowen Xue, Department of Epidemiology and Public Health, UCL.

Xiamen University (2017-2020), Master of Public Health

- Core modules included Advanced Health Statistics, Advanced Epidemiology and Senior Health Service Management.
- Final-year dissertation on 'Heterogeneous health groups and healthcare utilization among older adults in China' based on research carried out on the Chinese Longitudinal Healthy Longevity Survey.

Anhui Medical University (2012-2017), Bachelor of Management

- Major in Public Service Administration, concentration in Healthcare Management.
- Core modules included Social Medicine, Epidemiology and Healthcare Management.
- One-year training on basic knowledge and operation of Clinical Medicine.

Teaching experience

Teaching assistant, Xiamen University (Jul 2018 – Aug 2018)

- Course: Big data mining technology in health care.
- Prepared the computer workroom and slides for teaching sessions.
- Recorded attendance and provided help to students.
- Assisted with programme development and student assessment.

Work experiences

Head of the Public Relation office, Postgraduate Student Union in School of Public Health, Xiamen University, Xiamen (Sep 2018 - Dec 2019)

- Communicated and coordinated with other offices.
- Publicized events to students and staffs, including designing posters, taking photographs, writing newsletter etc.

Intern, Centre for Medical Big Data, Xiang'An District, Xiamen (Mar 2018 – Aug 2018)

- Applied statistical techniques on health data in Xiamen.
- Interpreted data and wrote reports.
- Provided assistance to related commercial companies.

Intern, Institution of Health Management, Anhui Medical University, Hefei (Jul 2016 – Dec 2016)

- Assisted in data collation and management.
- Prepared documents for weekly discussions.

Medical Intern, Chaohu Hospital of Anhui Medical University, Hefei (Mar 2014 – Dec 2014)

- Recorded medical documents.
- Conducted physical examinations.
- Assisted in surgical operations.

Field experiences

Press writer, Team of College Students¹ Summer Holiday Social Practices, Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region (Jul 2019)

- Investigated the prevalence of NCDs among impoverished communities.
- Interviewed local doctors and citizens.
- Recorded daily events, took photographs and wrote newsletters.

Team Leader and Investigator, Status investigation of mild cognitive impairment among old adults, Xiamen (Jul 2018 – Aug 2018)

- Designed the structure of investigation.
- Helped with questionnaire interview.
- Interpreted data and wrote the programme report.

Leader of Investigating Team and Investigator, Early diagnosis and early treatment of cancer in the urban area of Anhui Province, Hefei (Jul 2015 – Aug 2015)

- Organised daily trip and assigned work.
- Helped with questionnaire interview and data recording.
- Coordinated with local facilities.

Research skills

- Analysis and mathematical modelling in R and SPSS.
- Leadership and Management.
- Photography.

Publications

- Ye L, **Luo J**, Shia B-C, Fang Y. Multidimensional Health Groups and Healthcare Utilization Among Elderly Chinese: Based on the 2014 CLHLS Dataset. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2019;16(20):3884. doi:10.3390/ijerph16203884
- Zeng Y, **Luo J**, Ou L, et al. The impact of medical insurance on medical expenses for older Chinese: Evidence from the national baseline survey of CLHLS. Medicine. 2019;98(39):e17302. doi:10.1097/MD.000000000017302
- Ye L, **Luo J**, Shia B-C, Fang Y. Heterogeneous health classes for older adults and their regional disparities in China: based on multidimensional health. Public Health. 2020;178:15-22. doi:10.1016/j.puhe.2019.08.023

Conferences

- The Aging & Public Health program of the American Public Health Association's 2019 Annual Meeting and Expo.
- The Gerontological Society of America's 71st Annual Scientific Meeting.

Awards

- Outstanding Graduates 2020
- Excellent Merit Student 2019

References

Professor Anne McMunn - University College London, a.mcmunn@ucl.ac.uk
Dr Baowen Xue - University College London, baowen.xue.10@ucl.ac.uk
Professor Ya Fang - Xiamen University, fangya@xmu.edu.cn